MOHAMED HMINI

 $+(44)7570159076 \Leftrightarrow Llandudno, UK$

mo@mhmini.com \leq linkedin.com/mhmini \leq www.mhmini.com

INTRODUCTION

Experienced MLOps Engineer with a 3-year background in Data Science, Data Engineering, and DevOps with Degrees in Software Engineering and Intelligent Systems. I love problem solving and most importantly novelty when it comes to challenges, My cross-disciplinary skills help me to communicate effectively with colleagues from other disciplines. Actively seeking full-time MLOps positions.

EXPERIENCE

1. MLOps Engineer

Viridien

Jan
 2023 - Present $Llandudno,\ UK$

- Productionising our ML System with packaging, containerization, CI/CD K8s deployments.
- Actively optimizing our ML Pipeline to run efficiently on Azure as well as on-prem.
- Redesigning our system for better scalability, transitining from Spark to Argo workflows and to a Producer/Consumer design, as well as supporting running Models in an Offline mode.
- Building and optimizing an Azure Blob Storage events python listener.
- MLOps, Building an end-to-end Model Deployment CI/CD template to be used to deploy all of our models.
- MLOps, Building a tool to be used for Model Monitoring in production.
- Tools: Python, Spark, Argo, K8S, Docker, Gitlab CI/CD, Azure, Nuclio, Neo4i, Prometheus, Grafana, Mlflow, etc

2. Data Engineer

Viridien

Apr 2022 - Jan 2023 Llandudno, UK

- DevOps, coming up with adequate git branching strategies, helping with setting up CI/CD pipelines, dockerizing software.
- ML, modeling, building, testing and deploying machine learning models.
- Tools: Docker, Gitlab CI/CD, Python, Plotly Dash, Pytorch, etc

3. Data Engineer

Jan 2022 - Mar 2022 Casablanca, Morocco

EVEAD Group

- Building a google search based sitemap generator using selenium.
- Mimicking human behavior while browsing (dodging bot detections).
- Tools: Python, Selenium, Docker

4. Machine Learning Intern LaBRI

Mar 2021 - Sep 2021 Bordeaux, France

- Synthesis and learning of boolean networks for predicting cellular differentiation.
- Creating Different Boolean Networks' Embedding techniques to allow for a multilevel view of the same Boolean Networks' ensemble.
- Applying Feature Selection techniques to isolate the good Boolean Networks.
- Resynthesize new Boolean Networks using the learned rules.
- Using Machine Learning to Optimize a rule-based symbolic A.i system.
- Contributing to BNeDiction code base.

EDUCATION

Master's Degree in Information Systems And Intelligent Systems (M2SI)

Bachelor's Degree in Information Systems And Big Data (BDSI)

ESTS, Morocco
9/2019 - 9/2021

ESTS, Morocco
9/2018 - 6/2019

DUT (Diplôme Universitaire de Technologie) Degree in Software Engineering

ESTM, Morocco
10/2016 - 6/2018

SOME EARLY PROJECTS

D-PandiSIM early 2021

Big data based pandemics distributed simulator, scoring network nodes using inverse PageRank.

Paysim Fraud Detection late 2020

Fraud detection using VAE and BNN networks, generating distributions of the output.

TweetsOLAPing early 2020

Implementing an end-to-end tweets ETL/Analysis pipeline.

IntelliWebWrapper early 2019

Intelligent web content extraction, extracting the main List Region (list of products).

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, Java, C, JavaScript, Prolog, Clingo, Lisp, SQL, etc

Programming Paradigms: Procedural, OOP, Functional, Distributed, Concurrent and Probabilistic

ML/Data Manipulation: Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Sklearn, Pytorch, Pyro, Scrapy, SHAP, etc

Productionizing: Git versioning Strategies, Docker, Kubernetes (k8s), Helm, Gitlab CI/CD, Azure, Mlflow

Other Skills: Optimization techniques, Symbolic A.i, Statistics, Machine Learning, Explainable A.i, Game Theory, Web Crawling, NoSQL, etc

Other Tools: Pyspark, Nuclio, Mlrun, Triton, LabelStudio, Alibi-Detect, Neo4j, KubeRay, Argo Workflow, AirFlow etc

Languages: English, French, Arabic